arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-20

Arnab Dey

Location: Gothenburg, Sweden

Mob: (+46) 0764516092

Mail: arnabdey009@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile

GitHub

Summary

 An accomplished professional with more than 14 years of proven experience as a DevOps/CloudOps/Systems Engineer in the Information Technology industry.

- Providing solutions for various business applications on public and hybrid Cloud platforms, using
 CI/CD pipelines, orchestration, infrastructure automation, and Agile tools.
- Managing large and complex development, staging, and production environments, with a strong focus on quality and automation.
- As a senior team member, mentored and supported many colleagues across different projects and domains.
- Well-versed in the SAFe framework and the roles and responsibilities of a Product Owner.

Skills/Technologies that I work/worked with:

Linux, Shell Scripting (bash), Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud, Jenkins, Gitlab, GitHub, ELK stack, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Ansible, Python(Scripting), Database management (Mysql/MongoDB), Jira, Miro.

Experience

Cloud Engineer - 'Stena Metall AB': August 2024 - Present

- Performing Security Audit on **Azure** provisioned resources and provide feedback to Product/Project
 Team.
- Performing Azure Governance tasks using Terraform (with Azure Pipelines) and/or Azure portal.
- Creating backlog in the Azure DevOps Kanban board by reviewing all Microsoft recommendations(Azure Advisor) in order to make sure that we don't miss any technical vulnerabilities, security threats or unnecessary costs.
- Working with Azure Services like Logic apps to automate certain tasks and have set up custom roles
 to restrict certain actions against Azure resources for non-contributing users programmatically.
- Also resolving incident and SRs as per SLA from the "Cloud Office" dashbaord in ivanti.

Senior Software Engineer (DevOps) - 'Capgemini Sverige AB': Sep 2021 → July 2024

arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-20

Upgraded On-prem hardware cluster to Kubernetes cluster using Ubuntu server(LTS), xCAT,
 Rancher Server and Rancher Kubernetes Engine(RKE).

- Created and prioritized backlog in **Azure DevOps** that aligns with the product vision and delivers value to sponsors and users.
- Worked on MLOps platform (developed on an in-house architecture) to figure out solutions for the Al Agile Release Train.
- Created development environment and feature for scalable computing of Azure Databricks clusters using IaC (Terraform) and GitOps.
- Defined and managed the product vision and strategy, based on stakeholder/sponsors' needs.
- Collaborated closely with the scrum teams and the scrum master to plan and execute sprints, review the work done, and provide feedback and guidance.
- Communicated with the sponsors regularly to gather feedback, validate assumptions, and demonstrate the product increment.

Senior Business Consultant (DevOps) - 'Tech Mahindra': Feb 2017 → Sep 2021

- Performed a wide range of activities such as providing solutions and implementing CI/CD pipeline for business applications hosted on public/Hybrid cloud platform, orchestrating Microservices using Docker, Kubernetes(Rancher and Bare Metal) and also by implementing GitFlow.
- Worked with Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Gitlab (as per requirements) and performed Continuous Integration/Continuous Development.
- Responsible for Log search, indexing and management using tools like Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana.
- Automated regular activities by writing Shell (bash) scripts, automated infrastructure provision through Terraform for hybrid cloud platforms and also resolved escalated issues.
- Accountable for preparing operational documentations, deployments SOPs and architectural diagrams.

Senior AEM Administrator (Cloud) - 'ICF Next': Sep 2015 → Jan 2017

- Managed public cloud-based Infrastructure(AWS) which hosted Production/Stage/UAT environments
 of the several clients' web contents by using Ansible/Shell script and also by performing various AEM
 Administration essential tasks as well.
- Implemented Disaster Recovery both at application and infrastructure level.

Unix/Linux Systems Administrator – 'Hewlett Packard Enterprise' : Nov 2011 → Aug 2015

 Managed Unix-based Cloud/on-premise(VMware) platforms in Systems & Storage environment for a leading American Transportation and Logistics. Prepared deployments SOPs and UML-based architectural diagrams occasionally as per demand. arnab-dey-resume.md 2024-11-20

Linux Systems Engineer – 'Axon Networks' : May 2011 → Oct 2011

• Worked in platform administration in Systems & Storage environment for a leading Indian Online Retail client. Accountable for installation, configuration, upgrade, downgrade, troubleshooting, performance tuning and administration of various Linux based servers.

- Jr. System Administrator 'Bobcares' : Nov 2009 → June 2010
 - Managed Linux VPSs and implemented DNS, DHCP, SMTP servers as per requirement. Performed troubleshooting for RAID/LVM issues.

Education

B. Tech in Computer Science – West Bengal University of Technology 2005 → 2009